wearedevs.net 2019-12-24

# WeAreDevs Privacy Policy

Effective December 20, 2018

When you use our services, you’re trusting us with your information. We understand this is a big responsibility and work hard to protect your information and put you in control.

## Things you create or provide to us

When you create a WeAreDevs Account, you provide us with personal information that includes your name and a password. You can also choose to add a phone number or payment information to your account. Even if you aren’t signed in to a WeAreDevs Account, you might choose to provide us with information — like an email address to receive updates about our services.

We also collect the content you create, upload, or receive from others when using our services. This includes things like messages you write and receive, forum thread you create, photos you upload, and replies/comments you make on posts.

## Information we collect as you use our services

### Your apps & devices

We collect information about the apps and devices you use to access WeAreDevs services, which helps us provide features like automatic product updates

The information we collect includes unique identifiers, browser type and settings, device type and settings, operating system, and application version number. We also collect information about the interaction of your apps, browsers, and devices with our services, including IP address, crash reports, system activity, and the date, time, and referrer URL of your request.

We collect this information when a WeAreDevs service on your device contacts our servers — for example, when a service checks for automatic updates.

### Your location information

We collect information about your location when you use our services, which helps us discover suspicious activity. Your location is determined by your IP address.

## Why WeAreDevs collects data

We use data to build better services in the following ways

### Provide our services

We use your information to deliver our services, like processing the terms you search for in order to return results.

### Maintain & improve our services

We also use your information to ensure our services are working as intended, such as troubleshooting issues that you report to us. We use your information to make improvements to our services — for example, processing the specifics to an error.

### Develop new services

We use the information we collect in existing services to help us develop new ones. For example, understanding what terms were most frequently used helped us implement new and convenient features into the forum.

### Measure performance

We use data for analytics and measurement to understand how our services are used. For example, we analyze data about your visits to our sites to do things like optimize product design.

### Communicate with you

We use information we collect, like your email address, to interact with you directly. For example, we may send you a notification if we detect suspicious activity, like an attempt to sign in to your WeAreDevs Account from an unusual location. Or we may let you know about upcoming changes or improvements to our services.

### User protection

We use information to help improve the safety and reliability of our services. This includes detecting, preventing, and responding to fraud, abuse, security risks, and technical issues that could harm our users.

## When this policy applies

This Privacy Policy applies to all of the services offered by WeAreDevs and its affiliates, including the forum and account. This Privacy Policy doesn’t apply to services that have separate privacy policies that do not incorporate this Privacy Policy.

## Changes to this policy

We change this Privacy Policy from time to time. We always indicate the date the last changes were published

## Advertisements

  * Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to your website or other websites.
  * Google's use of advertising cookies enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and/or other sites on the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of personalized advertising by visiting [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads). 

## Additional Data collection

### Hotjar

We use [Hotjar](https://www.hotjar.com/) in order to better understand our user's needs and to optimize this service and experience. Hotjar is a technology service that helps us better understand our users experience (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behavior and their devices (in particular device's IP address (captured and stored only in anonymized form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display our website). Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymized user profile. Neither Hotjar nor we will ever use this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user. For further details, please see Hotjar’s privacy policy by clicking on [this link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy).

You can opt-out to the creation of a user profile, Hotjar’s storing of data about your usage of our site and Hotjar’s use of tracking cookies on other websites by following this [opt-out link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out).

### Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics to better understand what pages are visited and how pages are interacted with.

You can opt-out of Google Analytics collection at [this link](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).
